but I want to tell you a story now and
it has these characters in it and so
this is a very important story and it's
it's called the Enuma Elish and it's the
Mesopotamian creation myth and it's
important for a bunch of reasons first
of all it's the oldest written story we
know of but it's also a Middle Eastern
story and the whole all the Abrahamic
religions emerged out of the Middle East
and so it's a foundational story it's a
story that sits at the bottom of our
culture now it has it has similarities
to the creation story in Genesis whether
the creation story in Genesis was
derived from it or whether there was a
whole variety of similar stories
floating around in the Middle East and
at the same time that were variants of a
theme we don't really know but it
doesn't read I don't think it really
matters we don't know how old the story
is we know how old it is in its written
form it's it's it's thousands of years
old in this written one maybe it's ten
thousand years old it's written for him
but probably not it's probably more like
five thousand years old but the thing is
is that a 5,000 year old story is a lot
that's written is way older than 5,000
years like we're used to being in an
environment where there's a million
stories you know because we have books
and movies and all of these things but
you know in it's slower moving and more
archaic cultures especially ones that
are just just have an oral tradition
it's not like there's a million stories
there's like 20 canonical stories and
god only knows how old they are there
was evidence linguistic evidence I just
saw a study on this last week someone
sent it to me showing that some of the
fairy tales that the Grimm brothers
gathered might be ten thousand years old
and that doesn't surprise me because the
the kind of depth that's in a good fairy
tale is so the depth is so the
profundity is so deep that
there's no way that someone could have
just conjured it up you know 100 years
ago it's there's layers and layers and
layers of meaning and they're basically
archetypal and religious in significance
and a Hansel and Gretel story is a good
example of that
um and Sleeping Beauty is a good example
about do a lot of the canonical fairy
tales are they're very very powerful
they pack a lot of meaning into a very
short and do a very limited amount of
time so so it was great that this was
unearthed and it was only unearthed in
the late 1800s so we haven't known about
this story you know for a long long time
and so it's it was a tremendously
exciting discovery on the part of the
people who who dug it up so I'm gonna
tell you the story so the primary
character in this story is a like a
dragon mother named time at and time at
you could think about her as half the
dragon of chaos and half the destructive
creative feminine so she you could think
about her as what's sort of on the
border between what's a known known and
an unknown in unknown and she's
construed as the mother of all things
now the mother of all things is like
what was revealed when the towers came
down it's this tremendously complex
background multi-level system of
operations that's always going on that
that identifiable singular things emerge
from now the Mesopotamians wouldn't have
said that because what they said was
this story because that's the form in
which their knowledge it had developed
to the point where they could tell a
story about it instead of maybe acting
it out or dreaming about it in some
sense you know but they couldn't
articulate it we can barely articulate
it now so there's time out she's viewed
as the mother of all things and she has
a husband named app sue who's her
concert very little is said about app
sue in this particular story and I think
the reason for that although I'm not
sure of this is that the Mesopotamian
civilization
was knew enough as a technological state
let's say because it they made cities as
a technological state that the meant
that myths of humanity hadn't figured
out how to encapsulate the nature of the
of a technological dominance heart there
was a sense that it existed but there
wasn't a sense of it as a care of
differentiated character that was
capable of doing all sorts of different
things I think that didn't emerge till
Egypt although I'm not certain that but
that's how it looks to me so absolute is
her husband now the way the mesopotamian
started the world and this is the same
way that the people who wrote Genesis
thought of the world they thought of
that the world was a disk you know what
what the world's like when you go
outside and you stand in a field it's a
flat field you look at the world it's
pretty obvious what it is it's a big
disk of Earth and then there's a dome on
top of it and in the dome art of the Sun
and the moon and the stars and then you
might ask well what's underneath the
earth and the answer for the
Mesopotamians was fresh water first and
then saltwater how did you know that
well if you drilled down then nah the
fresh water would come so obviously
there was fresh water down there and
then if you went to the edge of your
territory it's like well there's the
salt water so the earth was you know let
the earth roughly speaking was a disk of
matter resting on a disk of fresh water
resting on a disk of salt water an
absolute time that were the fresh and
saltwater respect okay and there now the
Mesopotamians thought that the way that
the that absolute time that gave birth
to everything was that they joined
together in sexual union it's like the
yin in the egg and it's very much like
that exact and that it was out of their
union that the the elemental gods
emerged and I think you could think of
the elemental gods as their their their
forces of nature and they're viewed
through their not personified because to
personify something means that you see
it as an objective phenomena and then
attribute human characteristics to it
and that isn't how people work what
happens is we
perceive human characteristics and then
only with terrible effort do we extract
out the objective reality from them so
we D personalize things when we become
scientific but we just naturally see
them as characters and you can see this
when you read books to kids you know
like everything's a personal train is a
person and a car as a person
the moon is a person and the Sun is a
person and you know you read stories to
children that have that as a
presupposition doesn't bother you at all
you know you can just fall right into it
that's no problem you know and in the
animations you see the Sun in the sky
smiling and bouncing along and it
doesn't bother you you know it's no
problem to look at the world that way
and there's some utility in looking at
the world in that way as we'll discover
so anyways and I think part of the
reason that we view things that way oh
yeah that was the other thing I wanted
to tell you about our perceptual systems
is that we we do have a social cognitive
platform intellectual platform which
means that our primary categories the
primary categories of our mind do seem
to be social so you could say that the
reason our mind evolved or no what you
could say that the fundamental selecting
pressures on our on our mind ensured
that the the primary substructure of our
cognitive ability was modules that could
understand social behavior men can
understand women women can understand
men men and women could understand
children children men and women could
understand the social world and that's
and that's that's what we're specialized
for and then it was only after those
systems developed hyper develop probably
under the under the force of sexual
selection that they became able to
separate themselves to some degree from
that underlying social cognitive
structure and start to see the world in
ways that weren't personified so but
what that means is that our natural
categories are still and anthropomorphic
and dramatic it actually turns out they
work so absolute time not nature and
culture is a perfectly reasonable way of
thinking about them now they would say
well
it's the interplay between nature and
culture that gives rise to the
primordial forces of nature
now those forces of nature would be to
some degree external like a storm or
like fire but they would be sucked to
some degree internal - like like the
fire of passion right and that and the
storm of sorrow because those are
natural forces as well and one of the
things that the ancients knew was that
man was created to serve the gods and of
course modern people think of that as a
superstition but that's because they
don't really understand how archaic
people thought archaic people thought
like Freud thought it's like yeah yeah
you have an ego fine you know and as
long as you're in a box within a bunch
of other blocks as the Eagle runs things
but as soon as we put you somewhere
where those boxes are gone it's the
underlying forces of nature that run you
hunger thirst
you know aggression sexuality and all
those things that are impersonal because
of course you have them and you have
them and so does everyone else so
they're impersonal and transcendent and
they're also eternal and so when the art
archaic people said and they usually
said this with sorrow that man was
destined to serve the gods that's what
they meant they meant that we were the
playthings of these unbelievably
powerful primordial forces that
manifested themselves within our lives
and determined our destinies and in an
in fact a Mesopotamian said that
specifically about the elder gods they
said they were they they were part of
that which determined human destiny
Marduk who we'll talk about in a while
was given the tablet of destinies
because when he was when he asked to
become top god he said well if I'm gonna
be taught to determine the destinies and
well we'll get to that so you kind of
got to know what these what these
archaic gods work and they were
personalities you know when you could
say well yeah yeah maybe it's a mistake
to attribute the qualities of
personality to a storm although it
depends on what you think a storm is
like a modern person would think of a
storm as an objective event that you
have subjective reactions
- and our cam person would more likely
think of the storm as the subjective
consequences of the storm plus the storm
all at once they would make that
separation so it's a lot easier to
personify something under those
conditions or to not to personify it but
- but to stay within the realm of
conceptualization that makes it a
personified force so the storm God is
something that you know that can instill
terror into your heart yeah fair enough
you know alright so anyways absolute
imap they give rise to these primordial
gods and I'm going to think about them
as forces of nature and I think that's a
reasonable representation for a variety
of reasons they're like the Titans all
right so they give rise to these gods
and the gods are their children and they
run about making all sorts of racket
they're making rockets and they're doing
this and they're doing that they're
building things and they're messing
about with things and they're they're
noisily engaged in their interactions
with one another and they're having
children and they're fighting about sex
and they're just making racket like mad
and then they do something stupid and so
they're annoying timeout as they make
all this racket she's sort of slumbering
down there in the depths leaving them be
but they make all this racket and they
annoy her it's like it's the
environmentalist myth by the way it's
exactly the same idea so you know human
beings were kind of dopey we're running
around gratifying our fundamental needs
and making racket and destroying things
and if we're not careful Mother Nature
will come flooding back and like wipe us
out it's like yeah that's happened in
the past it could happen but it's an
archetypal it's an archetypal idea it's
a mythological idea so fine they're
making racket and time that's leaving
the beat but then they get arrogant I
would say or careless and they they kill
absolute and they make their dwelling
place on his corpse now that's a that is
a brilliant brilliant symbolic idea
because what it means it means a bunch
of things but what
the things that means is that insofar as
the gods are because they're masculine
they're part of the representation of
the dominance hierarchy in the human
interactions within it that the idea
that that that that's all existing on
the corpse of absolute is something like
the idea that all of the natural forces
that are embodied within human beings
and driving them are resting on a sub
structure of dead culture and everyone
knows that because everyone said is
especially modern people they look back
at their culture and they think all that
thing's dead you know and we can rest
comfortably on its dead surface well
that's not right because if it's dead
well if it's dead logically speaking
it's not alive and if it's not alive it
can't adapt if it doesn't adapt then it
falls behind and gets full of errors and
it gets corrupt and starts to fall apart
and if it gets corrupted full of errors
and falls apart enough then chaos comes
back that's exactly what happens in the
Mesopotamian myth so they kill apps ooh
and they keep making rocket and time at
wakes up one day in space
oh they're noisy I don't like them that
much and now they've gone and done in my
husband which is order so I'm gonna wake
them out so the guards get wind of this
and they're not very happy about it you
know because after all they're gone but
she is the garden goddess / dragon that
gave them all life and the probability
that they'll prevail in a battle against
that which gave them form is very very
low so they're pretty damn terrified so
meanwhile time at is generating her army
and she generates quite an army and that
Mesopotamians lists out what she does
she she first of all picks for her
concert a new character named King mu
and King who is like the king of the
demon monsters so her old husband was
absolutely maybe he was order and her
new husband is like he's not someone
that you want to have around at all and
so he's basically put at the hand of
this phalanx of terrible monsters and
she generates like scorpion monsters and
crocodile monsters and all sorts of
things in her army so that she
wipe out these these gods and so well
this is happening the gods gathered
themselves together and they decide that
they'll elect a champion from within
their ranks to go out and fight with
time out and so they do that they send
one God out he comes back with his tail
between his legs roughly speaking all
right don't let his encounter with chaos
and then they send another God out the
same thing happens and they send another
God out the same thing happens and it's
getting pretty damn hopeless because
they're sending out their best men
against chaos and them and the mother of
all things and they're getting
stubbled all the time while this was
happening they continued to produce new
generations of gods and at one point
this new god emerges as a young person I
presume um but he's there's some things
that are different than about him than
any other thing that's being produced so
far and one of the things that's
different is he's quite tall and
powerful so you know that's not
necessarily so radical but he has eyes
all the way around his head and when he
speaks he can speak darkness into being
and he can speak light into being so so
things obey the commands of his words so
he's a master of language he can see
everywhere and he's a master of language
okay and so the gods are checking him
out they think well you know he's he's
quite something maybe we can get him to
go after time mats so they all go to him
in this in this little group and they
say look Marduk cuz that's his name um
you know we've been checking you out and
you're looking pretty impressive and so
we've got a proposition for you how
about if you go fight time out and
Marduk who's not only all-seeing and and
very capable with language is no fool
and he says yeah yeah yeah I get what
you want but here's the deal you get
everybody together first and I'll go
fight your monster but you're gonna have
a Congress and at that Congress you're
gonna elect me king of the gods and then
I'll go fight time app and so of course
the other gods aren't very happy about
this but they go off and they have a
Congress and they invite Martic to it
and they talk about it and they realize
they don't really have any other choice
so they decide that they're going to
elect Marduk to the top of the hierarchy
of gods now that's such a smart idea
so if you think for example you can
think of a hero and then you could think
of you took ten heroes and averaged them
out of that you get a a god right so B
ten heroes you can Aneta here out of
that and that would be a god and then
maybe you do that to ten sets of ten
heroes and you get ten meta heroes and
then you take all those meta heroes and
you figure out what's the same about
them and you abstract that out and then
you get the hero of Heroes of Heroes and
that's the archetype that's the
archetype it's a process of distillation
it's like who's the most interesting
possible most interesting and capable
possible person well that would be this
person this is the most memorable
possible person well we don't know who
that is but this is how we figure it out
now I could say well I admire something
about you and I admire something about
you I can notice that as a
phenomenological fact you seem very
capable in a certain way and you know
you have this attribute and then I might
say well if I was gonna a sort out an
ideal for myself to follow then I take
the good parts of all of you and I put
that into one thing and then I would
make that my ideal well that's the
origin of the idea of the savior of the
Messiah
that's an emergent idea it emerges when
people notice that the hero is that the
hero is part of the force that makes
order out of chaos or sometimes the
reverse when when order has become too
rigid
you can also decompose order bring a
little necessary chaos into it and
rejuvenate the whole structure so
anyways so Marduk he gets elected King
now you might think about how would this
happen historically speaking well here's
an interesting way of thinking about it
so imagine a landscape that consists of
tribes okay and then on top of them
imagine a landscape of the imagination
okay so each member of each tribal group
lives in their imagined world and that
imagined world is full of dandies and
natural forces of various kinds that
they're following but then you can
imagine that as the tribes battle it out
and organize themselves the figures of
the imagination do exactly the same
so as the people are battling the gods
in heaven are battling which is also a
very common mythology and as the human
beings
beat themselves into a functional group
their world conceptions do the same
thing and so over time you move from
polytheism roughly speaking to
monotheism as the the as all these
tribes communicate with one another
in language and in and in combat and
sort out just exactly what should be
sovereign what should be powerful what
should be dominant right it's a major
it's a major issue and it's partly
practical it's partly conceptual so if
this is reflected in the Mesopotamian
creation myth the gods assemble
themselves and they look among them and
they think okay well someone here is has
the characteristics that should should
be the central element of the top deity
which is like the ultimate value
okay well the Mesopotamians chose wisely
vision and language
those are your most the most potent
weapons you have against chaos because
you if you pay attention you can see
chaos when it first emerges and then if
you are a master of language you can
encapsulate it and articulate it very
rapidly and you can communicate that to
other peoples it's like now this is it
you just cannot overestimate how radical
an idea that is it's a staggeringly
radical idea that that's the set of
attributes that should be at the top the
Mesopotamians are trying to figure out
what should be sovereign what should be
above everything else well you might say
a person it's like yeah yeah no the
person embodies sovereignty sovereignty
itself is something else
so in Fran's de Waal for example he was
watching chimpanzees hash it out for
dominance in in in the zoo and I think
it's in the homeland Arnhem I think
anyways it's a zoo that has a lot of
chimpanzees in that he spent a lot of
time watching them and you know one idea
about the dominant chimp is that he's
just biggest meanest like most
tyrannical chimp it's sort of the
strongman
of chip leadership but what do all
observed was that well that was sort of
true in that the strongest and meanest
chimpanzee could obtain dominance but
the problem with him is if he was really
like selfish and cruel was that he
didn't have any friends
now chips have friends and they spend a
lot of time with them and they groom
each other and they protect each other
in fights and like you can be the
ugliest meanest chimp around but if
there's two chimps that are
three-quarters your strength coming at
you it's like you you lose now so that
means two chimps that are capable of
enough civilization to bind themselves
in to a dyad that is that has mutual
obligations across time is way stronger
than one ship who doesn't and so what
that means is that strength and
viciousness you know there will be times
when that can emerge as the dominant
power buts very very unstable and and
everyone's motivated to bring it down as
fast as possible and the best way to
bring it down is with the coalition and
so partly what that indicates is that
it's actually the chimp who's the best
at making coalition's that's most likely
to become sovereign so that and that's
actually what happens with the chimps is
that the dictator chimp is very unstable
in in the one story I read of Arnhem at
the arm zoo he rose to the top though
you know bad bad guy that gangster guy
and two chimps went after me torn to
pieces they tore off his testicles yeah
and you know it agitated the hell out of
the rest of the truth and it was looking
like a bloody revolution you know it was
really really stressful for the truth
but but what it indicates and it's so
interesting is that the idea that in a
in a dominance hierarchy what's most
dominant is a power that there's no
evidence whatsoever that that's true and
in fact I was talking to what I have a
partner in a business that I have who
was a student of mine at Harvard he's a
very very smart person and I was talking
to him about dominance hierarchies and
he said something very that I found very
upsetting on a variety of levels he said
it's not a dominance herky if you can't
put a dog collar on the person
one level below you which is pretty
bloody blunt statement but when he's
prone to that sort of thing but what he
meant is that it's possible that the
idea that the term dominance hierarchy
is not the right term to be applying to
these sorts of social structures because
what it implies is that what keeps the
structure in place is power you know and
that's the sort of claim that people
like Foucault make it's all about power
it's like the thing is it's not all
about power it's not all about power
it's not all about power among animals
so with power with chimps if that's all
you've got is power you're gonna get
wiped out you have to so what do all
found was that the chimps who were able
to establish stable patterns of
leadership were quite congenial they had
a lot of allies so they engaged in
mutual grooming and a lot of social
interaction and they were very
positively predisposed to the females in
the troop so that's pretty interesting
you know because we don't know what
constitutes valid sovereignty but even
in animals it doesn't seem to be power
so and then you know you look at wolf
pack's and that sort of thing and you
know if two wolves go at it fur for
dominance one wolf will back off and
roll over and show his throat and you
know like Stalin wolf would just tear
out his throat but you know Churchill
wolf let's say would say well yeah
you're kind of useless but we might need
you around later so why don't you get up
and you know we'll let bygones be
bygones and that's what wolves do you
know and and unsurprisingly because what
are you gonna do kill everyone in your
troop well that doesn't seem like a very
effective strategy either for mating or
for survival
so the Mesopotamians are trying to work
out practically who's going to be
sovereign and at the same time
conceptually what is the proper basis
for sovereignty which is it's really the
ultimate question in some sense so
anyway so they elect marnik and the
Martok's got all these eyes and he can
speak and so he thinks all right he says
if I win I'm gonna get the tablet of
destinies and then I'm talking God and
they say yeah yeah whatever if you win
no problem so she goes out to fight
timeout and he takes a
a sword and he and he takes a net and
they meet on the battlefield and he
encapsulate Stimac in a net which i
think is a brilliant brilliant metaphor
again because chaos is amorphous and
unformed right and if you want to
conquer it you have to encapsulate it
within a net a net one you have to you
have to make it into something rather
than something amorphous you know and so
look maybe a client comes to me and they
say oh I've been having these terrible
symptoms on my heart races and I am my
breath I can't catch my breath and I
think I'm going to die and I think maybe
I'm having a heart attack and I'm always
at the hospital and they tell me that
there's nothing wrong with me and but I
have and like I'm I'm afraid all the
time and I'm starting not to go out and
I say oh you have a graph obeah lots of
people have that you're not the only
person like that in the world not only
that it has a name we know what to do
about it and there's a treatment course
and they go and the reason for that is
that the unknown unknown has just been
turned into a known unknown and that's a
massive improvement and so the person
who conceptualizes the anomalous
situation fastest is in fact the leader
that's the definition of leadership it's
like we don't know what's going on
this is what's going on and what and
when you say this is what's going on you
also simultaneously say here's a million
other things that could have been going
on that aren't so it's a process of
radical simplification and it lowers the
stress levels immediately anyway so time
that goes and or an article is he gets
her in a net and then he splits her in
half and he makes heaven out of one half
and the earth other the other for the
human beings and and he goes back to and
he defeats Keo and all the monsters and
then he goes back to tell the other gods
and they're pretty happy about this and
king who had the tablet of destinies but
Martic took that from him and now he has
it so he gets to determine destiny and
he makes human beings out of King who's
blood which is quite an interesting
little twist to the story and he makes
them to serve the gods and so so that's
that so
so the idea is that the hero who can see
and can communicate is also the hero who
separates out the elements of existence
so that it becomes a habitable place and
that humans should serve that serve
Marduk we have to serve something well
you're going to serve a natural force of
some sort you can be all anger you can
be all lusty can be all love we gonna be
all hunger or you gonna represent some
integrated some some balanced and
integrated emergent property of that
that's also socially constructed you
know so that you're a balance of natural
forces and you're a civilized person and
that's some sort of essence and that's
what you're going to strive for well
that's Martin so you're supposed to be a
good Marduk now Margaret is immortal now
the only person who was identified with
Marduk in the Mesopotamian realm was the
Emperor now they lived in a walled city
and so what the Emperor
the reason the Emperor was sovereign was
because he was supposed to be the
embodiment of Marduk on earth which
meant that his job was to transform
chaos into order
whenever chaos threatened he was
supposed to transform it back into order
so this is what the Mesopotamians did at
the New Year's celebration when the Year
is rejuvenated right the old year dies
of course we know that because we still
do it and the new year is this new baby
it's a time of new beginnings so the
Mesopotamians would take the emperor out
of the city and they'd strip him of all
his emperor clothes and then they'd make
him recite all the ways during the last
year that he'd been a bad Marduk like he
hadn't kept he hadn't been encountering
chaos properly and hadn't been keeping
order property so he had to confess all
of his inadequacies then the priest
would whack him with a glove as a you
know as a ritual punishment and then
they take all the statues out of the old
guards out of the city and then they re
represent the battle between Marduk and
Tiamat and then the Emperor was Martic
and he would win and then he would have
sex with a ritual prostitute which was
that this is a much tougher concept but
it's it's a way of symbolizing the fact
that if the creative force in
counters the positive element of the
feminine it's like the prince in
Sleeping Beauty getting Sleeping Beauty
from the grasp of the Evil Queen who
turns into the dragon it's exactly cuz
it's weird right you've seen that and
you understand it right Sleeping Beauty
is all in the tower she's covered by
she's hemmed in by a huge fields of
thorns the Evil Queen is trying to stop
the fish from getting to her she turns
into a dragon which makes absolutely no
sense but everyone follows it and then
he has to fight his way through that to
get to them to the main it's the same
idea in a different context and then
ordered productive order being
reestablished everybody goes back into
the kingdom and it's renewed for the
next year and that's the idea behind
Mesopotamian sovereignty and it's bloody
brilliant because it's an absence the
beginnings of law in some sense it's
it's the idea that to be to be proper
even if you're a despot even if you're
the king there's a sacred pattern of
behavior that you must adhere to which
is the consequence of a congress of the
gods deciding what the most effective
mode of being is it's staggeringly
brilliant and and it took that story we
just have no idea how long that story
took to emerge I would say it's it's the
consequence of the full course of human
evolutionary history like the there are
elements in it that are as old as
mammals and maybe older than that you
know if you think about those patterns
being embedded in behavior long before
they were abstracted out into
representations it's unbelievably
archaic and ancient and so you have time
at the Great Mother you have absolute
the Great Father you have Marduk the
archetypal son you have King oh who's
the negative element of Marduk right and
you have the drama of all those
characters interacting across time and
that's that's the myth alone that's the
mythological representation of reality
and taya math to tie it into the neural
psychology that we talked about you know
we talked about anomaly right and how
would normally you have a box that
you're in that is your world but that
box doesn't contain
anything in the world there's a lot of
things that aren't in it and sometimes
they poke their head in like a snake and
then that's disruptive and what do you
do well you have to you have to
voluntarily encounter the snake and
either defeat it or make something
valuable of you know you could cower and
hide but all that generally means the
snake grows and grows until there's
hardly any you in the box and there's
all snakes and that's actually the best
of Damien's story it's like if the Elder
Gods weren't so careless and had been
paying attention and hadn't killed
absolute time that would have stayed
asleep the whole time so mom so that's
the that's the level of isomorphism so
what's what's fascinating but I think
inevitable is that the mythology
reflects the physiology but how could it
not the physiology produced the
mythology like of course that's going to
be the case it shouldn't be a surprise
it should be it should be that we should
be the reverse should be a surprise it's
like there's no relationship between
these these old stories in the way that
human beings are structured it's like
well no no that's a dumb idea so
well that's the mesopotamian creation
myth and it's it's a killer it's it's a
it's a staggering story and you know it
still sits whether we know it or not
it's it's at the very base of our
culture it's absolute that's story and
if we kill it which we will or have been
then then look out you know we know the
story from so long ago if you let your
culture die and act carelessly towards
it all hell will break loose and it's no
joke so so here we are trying to
revivify it it's pretty weird that these
things happen to be real but then if you
think about it well how could it be
otherwise
you know you think all these people who
live before us for the tens of millions
of years that you know we've had our
FEGLI human producers were stupid they
weren't and they weren't ignorant and
they weren't superstitious or any of
those things they were they were they
were tough enough so that we're here